Oh brother.
Despicable Me 3 is a action, animation, comedy film directed by Kyle Balda.
Gru and his wife Lucy must stop former '80s child star
Balthazar Bratt from achieving world domination.
Gru / Dru (voice), played by Steve Carell.
Lucy Wilde (voice), played by Kristen Wiig.
Balthazar Bratt (voice), played by Trey Parker.
Margo (voice), played by Miranda Cosgrove.
Edith (voice), played by Dana Gaier.
Agnes (voice), played by Nhev Scharrel.
Despicable Me 3 is a 2017 American animated comedy film directed by Pierre
Coffin and Kyle Balda and written by Cinco Paul and Ken Daurio.
Produced by Illumination, it is the fourth feature
film in the Despicable Me franchise.
The film stars the voices of Steve Carell (in a dual role), Kristen Wiig, Trey Parker, Coffin,
Miranda Cosgrove, Steve Coogan, Jenny Slate, Dana Gaier, Nev Scharrel and Julie Andrews.
In the film, Gru teams up with his long-lost twin brother Dru to stop Balthazar Bratt, a former child
actor of the 1980s, from destroying Hollywood after his show was canceled years ago.
Development on a third main Despicable Me film began in 2013
with Coffin returning as director alongside Balda.
The film was in the early writing stages by 2014,
while the cast was announced in 2016.
Heitor Pereira and Pharrell Williams returned to compose the score.
Despicable Me 3 debuted at the Annecy International Animated Film Festival on June 14, 2017, and
was theatrically released in the United States on June 30, by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics, and grossed $1.035 billion worldwide, becoming the fourth-highest-grossing
film of 2017 and the fourth-highest-grossing animated film of all time during its theatrical run.
A further sequel, Despicable Me 4, was released in 2024.
The film explores themes of prison, villain, twin brother, sequel, jail.
The tone is lighthearted.